AKSHAY KUMAR KARANAM

iOS Developer

iamakshaya96@gmail.com



Bangalore

₹ TECHNICAL SKILLS

Xcode
iOS development
Swift
Basics of Objective - C
C language
Basics of Java

INTERESTS

Watching movies
Listening to music
Internet surfing



EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Software developer with 17 months of experience in mobile application development on iOS platform. Expertise includes design, development and test of iOS applications across Education, Hospitality and Healthcare domains. Successfully deployed iOS applications on Apple Appstore and received 4+ ratings consistently with good feedback from client and customers.



EXPERIENCE

Talentmicro Innovations Pvt Ltd

iOS Developer July 2020 - Till date

Papple Technologies Pvt Ltd

iOS Developer March 2019 - June 2020

Centura Technologies

iOS Developer Trainee *January 2019 - February 2019*



PROJECTS

Crashmeal

App published on Apple Appstore.

Crashmeal enable you to connect and place orders with restaurants and other food and beverage providers who advertise their goods through the Services (each, a "Food Point") and arrange for delivery of customers order based on their instructions.

Size of the team: 2

Role/Responsibilities in the project:

- Creation of User Interface in storyboard.
- Implementing tableview, collection view, tabbar controllers.
- UI and form validation.
- API integration.
- Testing and bug fixes.

Crashmeal Partner

App published on Apple Appstore.

The Crashmeal Partner for Business puts the power in the hands of the business owner. With an easy-to-use interface and powerful features, it helps you get the most out of your Crashmeal listing. Business owner can receive orders for food from customers, track revenue and analytics, manage outlet information, and more.

Size of the team: 3

Role/Responsibilities in the project:

- As a team member, was responsible for understanding functional, design and technical specifications.
- Implemented XL page stripper, tableview, collection view, and webviews.
- API integration.
- Testing and bug fixes.

Rarome

App published on Apple Appstore.

This app was created to support our work in general schools. Principals and teachers of the school can inspect students' information through this app. Students use this app to receive instruction from the school and it guarantees real-time communication between students' parents and teachers and can share student's information in real time.

Size of the team: 1

Role/Responsibilities in the project:

- Understanding functional, design and technical specifications.
- Implemented tableviews, collection views, webviews and payment URL integrations.
- Implemented Youtube player, VLCMediaPlayer using cocoapods.
- Design architecture for application.
- Testing and bug fixes.

Social Sign-In

This app is created to make the user signln using Facebook & Google in the app. Fetching the user data from Firebase Real Time Database using Firebase.

LifeAlert

This is a watch app which helps the user to track the health data like sleeping hours, steps, heart rate etc using Healthkit and Watchkit. Custom Siri shortcuts are also added using Sirikit.



EDUCATION

JNTUA

Computer Science & Engineering

2018

Nalanda Junior College

Intermediate

2013

Sri Vaishnavi EM High School

SSC

2011



PERSONAL PROFILE

Date of Birth : 20/04/1996

Marital Status : Single

Nationality : Indian

Known Languages: English, Telugu and Kannada.

